you know financial adviser take this
with a grain of salt this advice is free
and it's not worth that much so that's
you so you know but but one thing I will
say is uh just you know if you're
working for someone else then if they
have a matching 401k and you aren't at
least contributing to the matching level
you are throwing money away so if if
you're working for someone else and you
have a 401k get that money in there put
money in put more than they match and
just put away what you can uh and and
invest in that way now there are other
kinds of Investments that are higher
risk so there's Angel Investing and
venture capital and family Investments
and all that kind of stuff uh you know
loans and and pris and just there are
all these different um you know
financial instruments uh but really you
know if you don't have a solid base from
which to work that will feed you in
retirement you know then then you have
no business doing that high-risk
stuff and I I think when it comes to
investment a lot of people are scared
especially right now um with the you
know with the the whole outbreak with
the Corona virus and and whatnot and I I
think that people want to get out of the
Rat Race but they don't they don't know
how um from and I know you're not a
financial adviser but you know what like
what steps could they take to to get in
the right direction to educate
themselves yeah because it can be over a
lot of this information can be
overwhelming yeah you know I I'd say um
you know and I these are the two
fundamental things that I did over a
period of time I mean uh besides just
putting money in uh on a regular basis
but um uh don't bet on individual stocks
uh you know Tesla may go up and Tesla
may go down uh buy h mark market index
money market account so so look at
Vanguard uh and Vanguard had they they
really uh mastered this whole idea about
home market index accounts so look at
that and then uh you know don't time if
you ask me do people have an
opinion that uh the the climate isn't
changing yes there are a lot of people
with that opinion if you ask me if it is
fact that the climate is changing yes it
is
changing you don't have to say out of
86,000
seconds stage was the final stage where
they
[Music]
actually to see any
success engineering at
[Music]
media came out of both of those
things hey how's it going folks this is
Ryan Perez with go live and prosper
brought to you by the hustle Zone TV
network and of course uh the show also
brought to you by my company uh ww.bbc
creative.com and uh what we do is that
we help develop and Implement brand
strategies that are
counterintuitive empowered by first
principal thinking um I'm your host bran
Savant AKA Ryan Perez and I you know I
first want to thank you guys for your um
your support for our last show with
Antoine uh Watson it that was a really
good interview so thank you guys all for
sharing that live stream out and um you
know we've been growing um dramatically
on on Instagram so we're over I think
we're close to
34,000 uh uh followers in total I'm not
saying on one account we have several
accounts so you know almost 34,000
people are following us on the hustle
zone so I just want to shout out to all
of the supporters uh you know someone
was like have you been doing this for
five years I'm like I didn't even I I
haven't even counted I mean we've been
doing this for so long um and I just
enjoy you know connecting with all of
you guys and all of the different
mediums that we um we put our podcast so
um so again thank you guys all for your
your love and support uh today our guest
is a bestelling author key note speaker
and Coach he helps he helps
purpose-driven
Business Leaders to drive sorry to
thrive so that they can connect and
contribute at deeper levels Tony has
been personally trained in the science
of climate change for former vice
president Al Gore oh my God uh chairman
of the climate uh re uh reality project
the climate reality project is a
Grassroots network of more than 20,000
trained leaders who live and work all
over the world
and Tony is the executive producer of
the podcast social entrepreneur where he
shares positive stories from
underrepresented voice underrepresented
voices focused on Solutions uh social
entrepreneur is downloaded more than a
half a million times in over 180
countries he is a tedex speaker and the
bestelling author of crazy good advice
10 Lessons Learned From from 150 leading
social entrepreneurs um he is a former
Fortune 500 executive with companies
such as John I don't know how to
pronounce this last name John can you
help me go
Tony John
Deere uh medronic and Buffalo Wild Wings
he's he has an extensive experience in
strategic
planning uh talent management and
leadership development please folks
let's give it up for Mr Tony Lloyd and
that's Lloyd with one L right that's
right that's right it makes it easier
for people to find me online when
they're looking for me if they spell my
name with one L so it's t o n y l y d
awesome awesome well thank you for go uh
thank you for uh coming to go live and
prosper uh the first question that I
normally ask everyone is what is your
story so you have an impressive you have
an you have impressive resume yeah and
um but how did you get there you know
take me back from the beginning oh man
uh so I would I'm originally from
Arkansas and so you know like we're
number 49 in education woo you know it's
like you know one of one of the poorest
states in the nation you know um but it
was a good childhood right so I I grew
up in uh in Fairly poor circumstances
but you know in a good family uh I had
uh I had a technical career where I did
uh technical Consulting around
commercial nuclear power a very
engineering kind of uh career and at
some point somebody asked me to start
teaching other people about that so I
shifted from being the technical expert
to teaching other people about technical
expertise which led to a lot of other
things and a lot of other opportunities
and so you know my uh my degree now is
in marketing I uh had this corporate
career where I was recruited by John
Deere so the Big Green Tractors you see
out in the field or uh yellow
construction equipment or all that kind
of stuff uh I was recruited out of there
I went over to uh spin-off from ESS
Johnson and the name of that spin-off
was called Diversy and uh they make uh
you know cleaning sanitation other kinds
of products uh we uh we actually sold
that company to another company called
sealed air which freed me up I left that
I went over to medronic who makes
medical devices and I ended my career at
Buffalo Wild Wings which you know some
of your uh some of your fans might know
about Buffalo Wild Wings and and their
wings so through all that really uh I
think facilitating the growth of other
people was kind of that thread that
pulled it all together uh so I I'm a
really lucky guy Ryan I was able to uh
through savings and Investments I was
able to retire early so uh that gave me
an opportunity to do other things so I
you know I uh have the podcast social
entrepreneur uh I took some lessons
learned from that I wrote this
bestselling book called crazy good
advice 10 Lessons Learned From 150
leading social entrepreneurs and then
based on that uh that opened up a lot of
speaking opportunities so I've done a
couple of Ted X talks I do a lot of
Keynotes uh but the other thing that I
spend my time doing is coaching and
Advising other people on how to grow as
individuals and uh through their
business so today I I talk about the
fact that I I help purpose-driven
Business Leaders to thrive so in other
words to to take care of their
themselves so that they can uh connect
with others and uh contribute to the
world so that's kind of me that's my
background that's what I
do now uh take me back to when you were
a
kid how how it was like 150 years ago so
I don't 150 years ago yeah but no I I I
mean where how how were you raised
because I think that you know someone
that has such an impressive resume um
such as yours um you know you don't just
get there by yourself did you have you
know influenced by your family did you
have mentors along the way um you know
take me back as far as you can um to how
did you get that mentality for wanting
to help others and and to be successful
yourself yeah you know it's it's it's an
interesting question I don't think I've
been asked that so Ryan congratulations
to you that's a really good question I
think for me if you take my mom and dad
my family together you know my dad had
this really strong work ethic like he he
was a machine he would just you know
like he would he would go to work and
and he was raised in extreme poverty or
at least us-based uh level of extreme
poverty so he had this drive and desire
to pull his family up above that and uh
and he got us you know solidly into at
least lower middle class right so we
weren't we weren't poor but we weren't
exactly rich either um but he would work
like a fool and just you know hustle and
grind and all that and and I always
admired that hard work ethic now my mom
is this big-hearted kind person right so
she has good work ethic too uh and she's
this you know great person but you know
I grew up in the era of uh you know the
Civil Rights and Martin Luther King and
and you know we would sit in our living
room and watch the riots in Birmingham
and my mom would make sure I watch the
news and sort of teach me in that moment
and say you know look here's what's
happening here's what you see here's why
people are struggling here's what's
going on here's why this is important
and so she was this constant teacher for
me but mainly she taught me to be a kind
human being which is a great gift to
give uh but along the way I did have
mentors and you know Ryan I often say um
my the the whole secret to my career was
this people liked me they were kind to
me and they helped me to the next step
so all along the way I I don't think I
ever applied for any of the jobs I ever
had it was like somebody saw me they
knew me and they knew I'd be a good fit
for that and so they would just help me
along the way so I I live you know today
I live fairly much a life of privilege
right I was able to retire early I have
everything going for me uh and all of
that is due to uh something that I owe
to others that somebody help me along
the
way right that's that's that's amazing
now um what would you what would you say
about your special ability and if you
were a superhero you know what would
that special ability be that carried you
through was it your personality was it
your
smarts well I'm not that smart so it's
not that you know I I think um I think I
facilitate the growth of others so if
it's the skill set that I was born with
somehow uh whether I'm in a uh
leadership development Workshop or
Retreat or if I'm working oneon-one with
other people um my heart is about
facilitation so it's it's never been
about me that uh that I facilitate the
growth of others now in the last year
and we could talk about this a little
bit more I had to focus on self a little
bit more I had to pull back and and work
on me but really I think that's been my
secret sauce my superpower the thing
that I do uh that I think I do well and
that people appreciate and that they
have always um you know seen value in
that and why do you think they saw value
in that well I mean you right now you uh
you in the hustle Zone and you're go go
live and prosper you are here for others
right it's other orientation and I think
that um that that is a it's a key part
of success if you look at if you go to a
website and on the front of the website
it says me me me me me me you're just
going to tune out but if you go to the
website the website is all about you the
reader of that website or the visitor of
that website then you're going to be
engaged and and so you know um in our
podcast in my coaching and all these
things I always say we we want to inform
engage Inspire and then set people to
action
and so it's really it's not about me I'm
probably the least important person in
the conversation when I'm talking to
someone about business or growth or you
know whether it's their personal
development their business development
or their you know growing their impact
it's not about me and so that's really
been my
superpower that's awesome I I think that
um you know an old business mentor of
mine his name was Larry you know when
was when I started my first company
wasn't successful but you know we were
talking about the money we were going to
make because at the time we wanted to
create a social media Network and this
was before Facebook and uh Facebook and
Myspace and we're like oh we're gonna be
rich and I mean I was I was in my 20s I
didn't understand and here's this you
know he's my mentor and he says you know
um McDonald's doesn't count you know
because at the time McDonald's used to
put how many people they served on their
signs right and he's like you know you
never see McDonald's counting the money
you know they Count Their people and you
know that stuck with you know a a lot of
us is stuck with me because you know
really it is about the people because
you won't be able to reach as far as you
as as you want to go without people
lifting you up without people
compounding really right you know and
sometimes you know a lot of us when we
start when we start a business the the
ideas may be great but a lot of it is
you know it's my idea you know yeah yeah
this is what I want to do and and then
most most people fail because it doesn't
have the impact to reach the masses
right so I think you hit hit the nail on
the head there um wanting to to reach
out to people now
um when it when it comes to family life
yeah does family life um impact your
success at all yeah yeah so so the thing
of it is is um uh it all starts with
thriving right so I I said uh well let
me just back up for a second so in the
last year I went through this sort of uh
my year of personal best and we could
talk about that a little bit if you want
but but it really came down to here's
what I discovered Ryan I figured out
that we are here on Earth to connect
with others and to make a
contribution but you can't do those
things if you aren't practicing
self-care and so I when I talk about
self-care I talk about thriving but when
I think about thriving it's not me as an
individual it's me within a context
right so um so as I think about um you
know to to uh to
thrive uh I I look at my physical
emotional intellectual and spiritual
health when it comes to connecting I
think about my social my marital and my
parental duties right my family duties
uh and then when it comes to
contribution I think about my my
vocation my finances and then my
advocation which means my ability to
give back Time treasure and and and uh
money uh time talent and money sorry uh
and so you know it it's a whole thing
and and if you're if you're not if
you're not thriving within yourself if
you're not connecting with your social
your family your marriage or or
significant other and if you're not
making a contribution then somewhere
along the way something breaks because
it takes all those things put together
and you know I I'm a um I'm a big
believer that the answers are complex
because you know somebody said to every
complex problem there is an answer that
is simple and elegant and
wrong and so sometimes we we we are
tempted to say it's this one thing right
it it's it's only thriving it's only
myself that that matters or it's only
connecting with others that's all that
matters or it's only making a
contribution that's all that matters
those are sort of
monolithic answers like there's one
thing but the truth is it we we are
systemic we live within a system and we
Thrive within a system so so the answers
are a little a little
complex uh it's tempting to go with a
simple answer but I think when it comes
to family when it comes to my my
marriage my children my grandchildren
now you know that that is core to my
success
[Music]
now there are people out there that I
call one one hit wonders and I think
that we all know them we see them
because there are stories of people that
have just saw success overnight yeah and
um just by luck just being at the right
place at the right time yeah
um when you're talking to a young person
if you're mentoring a young person that
wants to be successful and they say well
Justin Bieber was able to make it you
um on YouTube you know what would what
would be your response um to that person
yeah you know um one one of the things
you you said you know they're they're in
the right place to the right time uh one
of the things that that that brought up
for me
is uh this is a phrase I use a lot with
people Miracles find you while you're in
motion right so if you're sitting on
your sofa and you're sitting on your
hands you're sitting still it's like
you're surrounded by this great cloud of
Miracles these really great moments of
serendipity these great coincidences
that happened right you're surrounded by
them but they can't see you because
you're sitting still it's the moment
that you go into motion it's the moment
that you start to take action that's
when those little coincidences show up
that's where those little moments of
synchronicity show up right um but when
it comes to that one thing you know you
said uh they want to be this one hit
wonder they want to do this one thing
and call it good it's really again you
know if you it comes to self it comes to
connections and it comes to contribution
it it's more than one
thing do do you believe in
luck well like I said miracles find you
while you're in motion right that that
that it's both you know um somebody said
uh and I like this that it's like
there's three buckets there's Talent
there is activity and there's luck and
you can't have zero in any of those
right so if you if you if you are a
little bit lucky and you know your
timing is right and all that and you are
working hard and doing all the right
things uh all that's cool but if you
have no Talent at it you know I mean you
mentioned the one hit wonders you ever
see those people who show up on
on you know the reality singing shows
and they show up and they start singing
and then all the judges like their faces
get this sort of like really weird look
like yeah maybe you should try something
else right right you know so you have to
have a little bit of luck you have to
little bit of skill and you have to take
consistent actions every
day now like the talent some people want
to going back to the one one hit wonder
yeah some people don't want to take so
so long you know to reach success and I
mean when you study you know uh VPS and
you study Executives you study CEOs and
founders of companies you know they were
in their respective field for maybe you
know 20 to 30 years before they went on
their their own but you know then then
you have guys like Gary vaynerchuk
that's saying that the rules are
changing so are you a like you know cuz
I mean for a young guy he's saying well
you know it's good and find and dandy
self-help and you know self uh self-care
and yeah you know uh but I need to pay
my I need to pay my my my rent right
right so yeah H how would you respond to
that yeah yeah you know it's great that
you brought up Gary ve because he he
started by making YouTube videos for his
family wine business right and he used
to do these same things for I think it's
called The Wine Library right and uh and
he used to do these YouTube videos and
he will tell you that he was probably at
episode 100 before anybody noticed he
was there so today we think about you
know oh well you do this one thing and
it goes viral and it spreads all over
the internet and all that I would tell
you that tiny habitual actions in the
right direction every day will take you
in where you're needing to go that uh
that sometimes you get lucky and
sometimes something goes viral but you
can't 100% depend on that luck you have
to do the
work most definitely and I just wanted
to shout out to all the people that are
watching we had five people in here uh
shout out to Mona Lisa uh and we have um
Rachel Johnson thank you guys all for uh
coming in to go live and prosper and
folks don't forget uh this is brought to
you by bowti creative uh.com you know we
handle all your marketing needs uh
graphic design um advertising web web
development and so on so forth so uh now
when it comes to you you mentioned that
you're that you were good with I I don't
know if we mentioned it offline or if
this was on the broadcast but you you
said that you know you had some good
Investments um and to help you retire
now how did you learn about
money yeah yeah I think that's a great
question Ryan uh you know the first
thing you have to do is not be afraid
right that that it you know we get all
creepy when it comes to money uh and you
know one of the one of the things that
um uh people say is never talk about uh
money or politics right so what we end
up with is a whole generation of people
that are ignorant about money and
politics and so I think it's something
we have to be comfortable talking about
a little bit um the other thing is it it
really it comes back to fundamentals
right so uh I have a few little you know
Investments here and there um that are
are higher risk but
primarily uh I look at index accounts I
try to buy the whole market and I put my
money in and I make small cont
contributions you know in a consistent
basis and build that portfolio and then
you know right now the market has been
taking a die because the Corona virus
and all that kind of stuff yeah it's
going to go down that's what happens and
so you just you just keep putting that
money in there because over a long
period of time you'll see some payoffs
from that so and by the way I'm not a
professional uh you know financial
adviser take this with with a grain of
salt this advice is free and it's not
worth that much so that's you so you
know but but one thing I will say is uh
just you know if you're working for
someone else then if they have a
matching 401k and you aren't at least
contributing to the matching level you
are throwing money away so if if you're
working for someone else you have a 401k
get that money in there put money in put
more than they match and just put away
what you can uh and and invest in that
way now there are other kinds of
Investments that are higher risk so
there's Angel Investing and venture
capital and family Investments and all
that kind of stuff uh you know loans and
and pris and just there are all these
different uh you know financial
instruments uh but really you know if
you don't have a solid base from which
to work that will feed you in retirement
you know then then you have no business
doing that high-risk
stuff and I I think when it comes to
investment a lot of people are scared
especially right now um with the you
know with the the whole outbreak with
the Corona virus and and whatnot and I I
think that people want to get out of the
Rat Race but they don't they don't know
how um from and I know you're not a
financial adviser but you know what like
what steps could they take to to get in
the right direction to educate
themselves yeah can be over a lot of
this information could be overwhelming
yeah you know I I'd say um you know and
I these are the two fundamental things
that I did over a period of time I mean
uh besides just putting money in uh on a
regular basis but um uh don't bet on
individual stocks uh you know Tesla may
go up and Tesla may go down um buy whole
market index money market account so so
look
Vanguard uh and Vanguard had they they
really uh mastered this whole idea about
whole market index accounts so look at
that and then uh you know don't time the
market don't try to put it in take it
out put it in take it out you know just
put the money in and leave it alone and
over a period of time you will
eventually come to the point where it
pays enough back that you can uh it's
like a salary so uh but but you know
again I'm not a financial ad a financial
advis and I I I think that
um I think what was my what was my point
there you had said something but you
know we I'll I'll I'll probably get back
to that so yeah now education
yeah you know a lot of the newer
entrepreneurs nowadays are um you know
they're saying you don't need to go to
college right yeah good question I
dropped out of high school right yeah
and um you know and I'm giving you
really easy questions because I think
that these are just I'm trying to get in
the mindset of today's entrepreneur yeah
right yeah uh they're not our M PA's
entrepreneur they're a new type of
entrepreneur so what do you think about
education and you know do you think that
that's important um to be a part of
thriving yeah it it's that's a great
question Ryan and again a good question
that nobody's asked me that um you know
I would say two things about education
so the first thing is you can get
started with nothing right so you can
start by you throw up a website you do
some lead generation you build an email
list and then you start selling into
that email list and that takes really
sort of a a different kind of education
right so lots of little certifications
or courses that people offer you know
little $27 books that you you know books
or courses that you buy you know you can
really learn a lot and you can you can
learn a lot from Dr Google so just go on
Google things right but there it comes
this point at which a whole well-rounded
education will serve you right when you
when you decide that you want to go
pitch to a bunch of people and you're
looking for some
investment having having a more
well-rounded education is going to serve
you in many many ways so um I I you know
I know a lot of kids who grow up and
they're great athletes I mean they're
just like killer athletes and so they
start saying I don't know why I need an
education I'm GNA go right into the NBA
or I'm going to go play football and I
you know so at the end the best and the
brightest take Michael Jordan take uh
Magic Johnson take well of course I'm
I'm sure I'm a age now but you know Take
Kobe who's no longer with us so so take
take these great athletes they knew that
there was life after Sport and so they
had to have the education to be able to
go do something now I I'm going to say
something that may surprise you I was 38
years old before I graduated from
college with a with a traditional degre
ree I had a technical degree but I was
38 years old before I graduated from
college and I and what I did was along
the way I was picking up a credit here a
credit there I was always in school but
they were like scattered everywhere so
what I did was I eventually went over to
Western Governor's University it's an
online university it's highly accredited
it is not you know uh so so about online
universities one is you have one model
where like they they sell you a course
and you have to sit through that course
for 6 weeks and then they sell you
another course and you have to sit
through that course for 6 weeks or 10
weeks or 20 weeks or whatever that thing
is right and and and it will bleed you
dry by the time you get through your
your online education there're also Fly
by Night companies that for like you
know send me $2,000 I'll send you a
degree it's like done right they're not
accredited they don't carry any weight
and you don't really learn anything
what I like about Western Governor's
University is they are highly accredited
they're highly structured and it's work
at your own pace so you sign up for six
months you get through as many credits
as you can you s it for the next six
as you can in 6 12 18 months you can get
through a ton of credits and then
eventually graduate so that's how I
ended up consolidating all those little
college courses I'd taken over the years
and all these different places you know
I I was doing consulting work and I was
on the road so I was never anywhere long
enough to stay and go through one degree
program in one college or university um
but I would encourage people yes get
your education and I just one more thing
about education as a corporate executive
there were a lot of times I wanted to
promote people in the company but our
company had a policy that said if you
don't have a degree you can't be in
certain positions and so it broke my
heart I would have highly competent
highly skilled individuals that I wanted
to give more money and more
responsibility to but we had a corporate
policy that wouldn't allow me to do it
so get that degree now you don't have to
do it all at once you don't have to do
it traditional way there are a lot of
different ways to do it but my
encouragement get that
degree well thank you so much for that
advice uh when it comes to time yeah how
do you value time and you know how
important is time to you yeah well I
mean uh the way we spend our time is the
way we spend our life right so so the
average
person uh
spends about a third of their life
asleep you know if you if you sleep for
eight hours a night not all of us do
right some do 10 and some do five but if
you sleep eight hours a night that's a
third of a day and then you go to work
during the work week and you spend 8 10
12 hours there so you're spending a
third of your time on the job so twoth
thirds of your time you're either asleep
or you are at
work and then when it comes to our
evening time or our free time what we do
with that makes a big determination so
if I want to think about the outcome of
my life I have to to think about how I'm
spending my time if I want to make an
impact if I want to make a difference if
I want to grow my relationships I have
to think about how I'm spending my
time time is very important folks and uh
we have nazim from Italy uh shout outs
to nazim thank you for for joining us um
so
Tony we are um reaching the hour uh but
before we go um let's talk about your
book okay so what's the name of the book
and what does it do yeah yeah so it's a
here let me hold it up it looks
something like this of course the light
shining on it you won't be able to see
it uh it's called crazy good advice 10
Lessons Learned From 150 leading social
entrepreneurs and so uh I have a podcast
called social entrepreneur and a social
entrepreneur is somebody who makes a
dollar but they make a difference right
so they
they um they do a business but the
business has a social or environmental
benefit to it and so I uh I have now
interviewed more than
250 uh uh entrepreneurs and then when I
hit the 150 Mark I ended up writing this
book and and what happens Ryan and you
probably get this is I get to the end of
the interview and I go okay what's one
key piece of advice one thing that you
can share with our audience and what I
found was the 10 same things get are are
offered again and again and again and so
uh so that's what the book is about it's
about uh these 10 lessons learned from
these 150 leading social entrepreneurs
and I took all that and I threw it
together in this book uh and then you
know there's also some supplemental
material online and you know we have a
Facebook group that goes with it and you
know there's some self assessments and
there's even some coaching available
with it and some other things so uh so
it's it's like the complete package you
know and how do people find it how do
the guest how do my guests find your
book how do your guests find it well
listen um I like bow tie creative I like
what you're doing um and so here's what
I'm going to do I'm gonna offer uh if
somebody will send me an email and I'll
give you the email in a second if
somebody will send me an email and if
they'll mention bowai creative and you
spell it with a K right creative right
so bow TI creative and uh ask for the
book crazy good advice I will send it to
them free of charge awesome so if they
wantate that if they want if they want
the paperback uh they'll have to pay for
the shipping and handling what it costs
me to print it and ship it to them uh if
they want the electronic version I'll
send it to them free of charge no no
problem uh and then uh once they get it
then they can access Facebook group and
the and the online assessment and maybe
even sign up for some coaching time or
whatever they want to do with that so so
it's um you know I I I really like what
you're doing Ryan and I really admire
what you're doing you know I I like the
hustle Zone I think it's very cool I
like your you know your podcast go live
and prosper uh you know but I really
like you I like your you know what
you're building I like your tribe I
think that uh you know when I was
looking around for people places I
wanted to tell my story this is one of
those places and I wanted to make sure
that I talk to you oh that warms my
heart that Wars my heart but you know I
I really appreciated this um uh this
interview I think that you know
we a lot of the things that you said
it's stuff that you know people who are
entrepreneurs already know but we we
need reminders and and we need reminders
from guys of the likes of yourself uh
you know because we just need to because
sometimes we know it but we just need
something to Ricochet back to us to say
Hey you know we got this and I think
that um if folks if you guys have uh if
you guys are just catching the tail end
of this um make sure to rewind this um
you'll also be able to find this uh uh
podcast on Google Play on Spotify on
Apple music and all of the the major uh
podcast networks uh now uh Tony we
reached the end of our conversation so
uh we have one more round of questioning
to go before you you go and this is our
lightning round lightning
round so need a sound effect for that
I'm working on
that like everyone all my guests are
like oh my God what is he doing is he
having a
seizure um so uh talking or
texting uh yes I I like to text but then
once a conversation goes to past a
couple of texts I I want to
talk awesome favorite day of the week uh
all of them uh no I you know it's
interesting because of the life I live
uh weekends sort of blend into weekdays
and um so I'd say any day that I uh I
get up I'm able to go out for a run and
have a good time that's a great day
awesome country music or Rock oh rock
rock
it's got to be rock yeah uh favorite
Fred favorite city in the US besides the
one you live in oh in the US uh besides
the one I live in um that's a great
question I I guess um it used to be
Boulder I would say it was it all right
so it's Boulder in 1982 that's what it
is you know like uh that cool funky Vibe
uh but I like Asheville uh North
Carolina I like uh you know I I like I
like hippie funky kind of towns awesome
awesome um last song you downloaded oh
my God last song I
downloaded
um um great
question pass
pass what is one thing that your wife
would say about you that no one else
knows oh that no one else knows oh my
god
um uh that I'm a good partner
you know uh I do you mind if I break the
lightning here for one second to tell
you one thing about that yeah go ahead
yeah that uh that my wife and I met
before there was an internet we met
through a newspaper advertisement she
put an ad in the newspaper that said
partnership
wanted and uh and I answered the ad and
that's how we met oh that's awesome and
you weren't scared because I mean we're
we're scared to even to sell furniture
on
Craigslist she could have you know you
could have been dead yeah respond to
that ad but what made you respond to the
ad uh well so it before there was the
internet before there was Tinder or
Bumble or any of these other kind of
apps uh there were in the newspaper
there were these things called personal
ads and so it was a you know it would
come out on the weekend and uh and and
the um and the
uh the like in her case she put in the
ad and then we uh men would go to the ad
and there was a a phone number to call
and a code and we would call this number
and put in the code and then uh we would
leave a message and then she would
decide if we sounded like a serial
killer or not and if we uh if we didn't
sound like a serial killer then she
would call us and this was even before
caller ID so you know we didn't know
what her number was even after she
called so she calls me up and we just it
was like magic like boom we were
connected uh and so we we had this
conversation on the phone we made
arrangements to meet uh and we met at a
a place and had I remember I had black
bean chili that day and uh we had she
was wearing purple and it was just it
was a great day great connection and
we've been together all these years
later oh what a beautiful story thanks
man I broke the lightning though it's
not not rapid fire here any yeah that's
okay that's okay that that was awesome
uh F favorite holiday uh
Thanksgiving how long does it take for
you to get ready for what for anything
think uh I roll out of bed ready man I
ready he's ready I am ready you know if
you need me to shower and brush my teeth
it might take a little bit longer but
otherwise I just roll out and I'm gone
you're gone that's I love that I love
that um fill in the blank Taylor Swift
is cool is cool at what age at what age
did you want to retire are you and I I I
will pass that question um last two
questions so invisibility or super
strength invisibility and why uh because
you can just you learn so much right I'm
a lifelong learner and you could just
hang out with people and not creep them
out that you're hanging out listening
yet yeah it's like oh now I know why my
attendant's not paying his rent on
time he's
struggling let me see if I can give him
a
hand uh and is it wrong for vegetarians
or vegans to eat animal
crackers that's a great question well
I'm I'm on a plant-based diet so I'd say
no it's
not um awesome well I'm on a plant-based
diet too and you know I was going that
was the question I was going to ask you
um I wanted to talk to you about climate
change yes this is um kind of a
deviation from our regular conversations
but uh it's your show man you just go
yeah I I I really want while I have you
on here um you know you did uh like you
you do have a history with climate
change and there's a lot of people that
you know I live in Alberta Al I live in
Canada and in Alberta we have the uh the
oil sands and there's a lot of people
frustrated with our with our government
Justin Trudeau uh because we don't you
know some of us don't believe that
climate change exists and we some of us
believe that it's propaganda right right
you know brainwashing and you know just
trying to get more tax money for carbon
taxes Etc so what's your you know what's
your opinion about climate change is it
real and how how can we prove this oh
wow uh well let's let's just start with
this uh if you ask me do people have an
opinion that uh the the climate isn't
changing yes there are a lot of people
with that opinion if you ask me if it is
a fact that the climate is changing yes
it is changing you know and and honestly
it you know I uh I I uh do these
presentations these climate reality
presentations and I do them all over the
place but uh you know um if you think
about sort of uh conservative and
liberal uh the the Twin Cities where I
live in the Minneapolis St Paul area is
very liberal uh but outstate is very
conservative uh you know so the people
who are outside of those Twin Cities uh
I get as much action on people wanting
to talk about climate change and the
reality of climate change and what we
can do about it in conservative areas as
I do in more Progressive and liberal
areas and uh and so it's mainly because
we talk first of all about values we we
don't talk about you know uh you know I
don't know political opinions or any of
that stuff it's about what do we agree
on right you know people who love to be
Outdoors people who love to play in the
snow people who love to um you know to
connect with their family in a healthy
environment people who are tired of the
tick population growing so much you know
like there are so many things that we
can connect on commonly around our
values and when we look at the reality
not the opinions but the reality of
what's Happening there's no denying
what's happening you know um and I will
say that there are a lot of people who
investing a lot of money and creating a
lot of propaganda to create confusion uh
and by the way they're using some of the
same brand agencies that created the
misinformation propaganda for cigarette
companies for a lot of years where
cigarette company Executives would sit
at the table in Congress and go well
we're not really sure that the science
is conclusive that you can connect
cigarette smoking to lung cancer we're
not really sure that that's been proven
yeah it was proven but they had a
misinformation propag g a campaign and
the same people who ran those campaigns
are running the climate change
misinformation campaigns
today wow and I I think that um you know
from and and I have people on the other
side of the the debate that you know
they believe that corporations are to
blame uh who do you
think at the end of the day I mean
there's we could point the fingers at
who's the blame but right you know do
you think that the government is
responsible um to lead the charge on
climate change do you think that
corporations um should are leading the
charge are you know do you think that
the free Market's going to just adjust
itself um you know to tackle uh climate
change well these are great questions I
think that what we've seen proven in the
past is that um it helps to have
government action um you know in the uh
in the
1960s in the United States if you went
into Los Angeles you could not see five
feet in front of you because of the smog
the smoke and and fog mixed in together
uh you know water was being polluted
there were all these you know phosphor
phosphor going into the water that were
polluting you know so so the American
people got really upset about that and
corporations were not self-regulating so
we passed the Clean Water Act and the
Clean Air act and those were passed by
the Richard Nixon Administration a very
conservative Republican administration
because we care about the Earth and
about our citizens yeah so I think you
cannot take away from the need for big
structural change LED by people in power
who have the ability to set the tone uh
at the same time I think it goes from
the individual action to the family
action to the Community Action to the um
you know and Business Leaders taking
action and my my uh show that I uh run
social entrepreneur we're talking to
people who are Business Leaders who are
taking action and in this upcoming
season I'm interviewing people about the
climate crisis and about big structural
change but also about businesses that
are coming up with Solutions so I think
you need Market forces you need
government forces and you need
individual forces to come together to
say this is important we have to pay
atten let's do something about it and
what would you say to um especially to
the people that live in my Province yeah
you know that are because our economy
has taken a dive because you know we
can't get pipelines passed Etc you know
what would be your response to them
because everyone's like you know how are
we supposed to survive like you know we
have the you know Alberta uh claims to
have the cleanest uh you know operation
um in all of the world and so what would
you say to some of the albertans here
yeah well first there are no jobs on a
dead planet right so if you if you care
about the economy if you care about um
you know the the Vitality of your region
it has to be about more than one thing
and um you know in uh so right now
here's a great debate that's going on um
I believe that you know electric
vehicles are a great instrument for
reducing the climate but to have
electric vehicles you have to have
batteries to have batteries you have to
have copper and the biggest repository
of copper is near the uh The Boundary
Waters which is you know a pristine
amazing area up in northern Minnesota
and uh you know I don't want somebody
going in there with a big shovel and
digging up Boundary Waters to get to the
Copper to put in the batteries so that
we can save the environment I don't want
somebody destroying the environment to
so so we need to have balanced
conversations where everybody's at the
table we need to have solutions that uh
take into account everyone's concerns
and yet at some point you get a voice
but you don't get a choice right you
know uh I I um here in the unit un
States we have you know big debates
about guns and uh you know uh so there
are a lot of people who believe that I
should be able to carry my gun anywhere
I want so so there's that ripping apart
well why do they want to carry the gun
it's really about safety so can we have
a conversation about safety that doesn't
necessarily lead to the one solution
that you have in mind can we have
conversations that are bigger than the
one thing so so I think that's the
conversation we have to have and and the
thing I said very early uh in this in
this conversation with you Ryan is I
said the answers are
complex and that having the one answer
you know well is it jobs or is it uh you
know or is it the climate the answer is
yes but to get there you have to you
have to take everybody's opinion get
everybody at the table and then move the
conversation forward and everybody has
to be willing to uh to collaborate on
these things right well thank you Tony
uh we have one more question from the
audience and we'll wrap it up um what do
you what do you guys think about the
virus epidemic we are freaking out over
here hospitals are not um able to handle
the amount of people that are coming in
uh well I'm not an
epidemiologist
uh I I I will tell you um I I think
reasonable caution is is called for um
you know I am cancelling a lot of public
events that I've been doing uh I am
staying home more I'm doing a lot more
uh zoom and Skype meetings instead of
going to places uh and so you know I
think that there's things that we can
all do I even noticed as I was as I was
uh being interviewed I looked I can see
myself on the camera and I noticed that
I kept putting my hands on my face oh
yeah don't do that you're not supposed
to be doing that you know so U but I I
think it's gonna have some big impacts I
think it's already having big impacts on
the market and I think that those
impacts are just now being felt and
we're going to see some bigger waves
coming from this and it really could
have a hard impact on the economy in
general and on a lot of other things so
you know when when somebody cancels a
big event uh then it's not just the
event uh venue but it's the vendors it's
people who are going to serve food there
and it's a people who do dry cleaning
and it's you know so so this thing is
having a big Ripple impact across the
economy and we're just starting to see
the early days of that uh so I think
it's you know wash your hands off and
don't tou your face do the common sense
things that they talk about uh and yet
find new ways to uh to continue moving
forward that that that's just my my
opinion on it and and you know am I
freaked out yeah of course I'm freaked
out it's a pandemic you know they said
they said on the news last night you
know uh the most likely people to die
from the virus are men over 60 I went
who wait a minute that's
me yeah well you don't look it well
thank you I appreciate
that yeah I it does it does freak me out
and um I did see people like but what
also freaks me out is is the
misinformation um the fake news and you
know I think the
hysteria in Canada here I don't know if
what it's like in the States but you
know we our Costco are out of toilet
paper yeah and I'm asking myself how
like you know we're talking about
climate change on one end but then we're
buying out all the toilet paper on the
other end right yeah yeah there's this
hysteria everyone's freaking out and I
think that there should be a balance of
information that you know the the virus
isn't um it's not that contagious it's
not like the flu
um you know and it does attack people
that have weaker immune systems and I
did you know one thing that I saw which
was funny I saw a guy uh with a mask
saying go vegan on the
[Laughter]
mask he's got mixed messages here he's
got Miss but what do you like what what
made you before you go what made you go
vegan uh well last year I yeah it's okay
uh so last year I um
I I had this well it's a longer story
but let me just say it in like 30
seconds if I can um last year I had a
real uh human crisis I um I was
depressed I was anxious uh I'd been
working a lot I felt socially isolated
uh and then you know when I was stressed
and and you know what it is when you are
uh an entrepreneur anyway that it's very
isolating work sometimes it's very
stress full you know you're trying to do
everything at once you're trying to grow
the business and you know so anyway and
I really came to this point where I was
anxious and depressed so I did a self
assessment and I assessed myself in
these three areas about Thrive connect
and
contribute uh and then I set a plan for
how I was going to improve in each of
these areas and so uh last year I did an
experiment and it's called my my year of
personal best
so what would my life look like if I was
living my best life physically
emotionally intellectually etc etc and
so uh when I when I did that experiment
uh you know I I went back to running I
hadn't run in a long time or I been
running but I wasn't serious about my
running uh I switched to a plant-based
diet uh you know last year in 2019 I
lost a total of 16.4 pounds which you
know you know is is pretty impressive
iive given that I'm not that heavy in
the first place right um let's see I
have I have a couple of other statistics
my LDL is down 29% my triglycerides are
down 38% my cholesterol is down 40% so
um and last year I ran
1,790 miles which is basically the
distance from Minneapolis to
Miami uh and uh and I set a new personal
best in 133 different race disc es from
the one mile through the marathon and so
you know uh and so now today when I'm
talking to people and I think about
thriving you know these are the kinds of
conversations that we're having with
people I have a self assessment that
people can take about how am I doing in
thriving in connecting and in
contributing and then I offer coaching
around that in the first coaching call
is free of charge and so that that's the
kind of work that I'm doing right now
that's amazing Tony that's amazing you
were our amazing guest you had a lot to
say thank you for for staying over the
hour uh and uh thank you guys all for
participating you know we had an active
chat today um yeah mainly nazim but he
says uh work has come to a complete halt
here in Italy yeah I I heard about that
in the news good I went on a diet in
July and super happy I think I you know
and I'm also plant-based as well and my
skin is so smooth and I
still I'm looking good and I feel good I
think the most important thing is you
know just being able to feel good and
feel um centered so uh but anyways Tony
thank you so much for for coming in on
to the onto the broadcast and what is
your email so we can uh yeah uh so sost
on the yeah Tony T N
Y Tony Lloyd t o n y l y d with one L
ly.com okay so reach out to me you know
uh mention bowai creative uh ask for the
book and I will send you you know the
book uh if if you want the physical book
you have to cover the shipping and
handling uh if you want the ebook I'll
send it to you free of charge and then
that'll give you within the book it has
a link to the Facebook group and uh some
coaching opportunities and some other
stuff uh As You Wish awesome well thank
you so much Tony and one more thing
before you go uh we do a call and
response so I'm going to say welcome to
the and then you I need you to scream as
loud as you can hustle Zone all right
you ready so welcome to the hustle
Zone I saw myself on camera I'm going I
look like the screen
face one of these days I'm going to do a
a um a compilation of everyone doing the
so it's gonna
be you can leave me off that if you want
yeah I will I look ridiculous enough as
it is I don't need any help to look
ridiculous okay sounds good well thank
you so much Tony and we'll talk to you
later okay thanks Ryan yeah no no
worries